MICHAEL KIRLIN

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

SUMMARY

I build stable, flexible, cost-effective platforms that let devs write code without worrying about how it's getting out into the world and what it's getting up to once it's out there. My perpetual goal is to automate as much of my work as possible. I mostly use Python for scripting, but I'm comfortable in a number of languages and willing to learn anything for a job. I can pinch-hit as a backend developer in Python, Ruby, or JavaScript. I'm a long-term resident of the AWS world and I keep up-to-date on the latest and greatest in the AWS universe. Because I've spent years clicking around hunting toggles in that console, I'm a zealot for infrastructure-as-code and I've worked extensively with IaC tools like Terraform, Docker, and Kubernetes. I believe in over-communicating, ideally in writing, and pairing frequently as a way to test my own thought processes and learn from and about my coworkers.

EMPLOYMENT

Tegus

Senior DevOps Engineer · Mar. 2022 to Current · Chicago, IL

- Built AWS infrastructure with Terraform, guiding developers on IaC best practices and automating changes using Atlantis in CI/CD pipelines
- · Administered multiple Kubernetes clusters, including creating custom Helm charts for streamlined deployments
- Developed Datadog monitoring solutions, creating dashboards and alerts for infrastructure and applications
- Reduced overall AWS compute spend by 30% after transitioning from EBS to EKS and evaluating cloud resource utilization with Datadog
- Created developer tooling for smoother deployment, monitoring, debugging, and interaction with Kubernetes-based applications
- Designed and implemented CI/CD pipelines for several teams, leveraging GitOps for continuous integration and delivery and improving developer workflows
- Set up unified CloudTrail monitoring, GuardDuty, and Inspector. Selected and implemented Wiz after running CSPM tool POCs
- Redesigned AWS networking configuration for improved security, including isolating databases and caches in private subnets
- · Authored comprehensive documentation, runbooks, and training materials on infrastructure, security, and deployment processes
- Contributed to the migration from Elastic Beanstalk to Kubernetes (EKS)
- Coordinated with external pentesters to secure the environment, remediating findings with development teams. Supported SOC2 audits by automating data collection

PayPal

Developer Relations Engineer · Aug. 2021 to Mar. 2022 · Chicago, IL

• Worked on the new Developer Relations team building internal applications and developing content for external developers using PayPal.

Software Engineer · Nov. 2020 to Aug. 2021 · Chicago, IL

· Worked on the Unified API team, building and maintaining a GraphQL API that was used for unbranded payments by some of PayPal's biggest customers

HERE Technologies

Senior DevOps Engineer · Oct. 2017 to Nov. 2020 · Chicago, IL

- Infrastructure and version control modernization through SRE engagements
- · Create service health dashboards and process automation, incorporating external tools into monitoring systems
- Manage existing infrastructure and deploys and deploy new applications or application revisions as necessary
- Create, deploy, and maintain internal applications to monitor infrastructure and applications

NextTier Education

Backend & DevOps Engineer \cdot July 2016 to Aug. 2017 \cdot Chicago, IL

Turing Group

Web Developer · Jan. 2015 to July 2016 · Evanston, IL

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp

Web Development 2014

Completed 19 week intensive web development program.

Creighton University

Master of Arts (M.A.) Education 2013

Creighton University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) International Relations and Spanish 2011

SKILLS

AWS services (IAM, RDS, EC2, EKS/ECS, Lambda, VPC, Route53, DynamoDB, S3, CloudWatch), Kubernetes, Terraform, Gitlab CI, Atlantis, Helm, Helmfile, AWS security tools (GuardDuty, AWS SSO, CloudTrail, Inspector, KMS, WAF, Secrets Manager), Python, Ruby, Technical Writing & Presentation, Docker